Miklos Rozsa Papers
Miklos Rozsa Papers
1918-2000
Rózsa, Miklós, 1907-1995.
90 linear ft.
Correspondence (ca. 1939-1995); compositions by Rózsa and others; fan mail (1940-1995); film music; memorabilia includes awards, financial and legal documents, personal documents, personal items, and photographs; printed materials include articles and clippings, concert programs, press notices, and publicity; writings by Rózsa and others.
Correspondents include Maurice Abravanel, Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, Joseph Achron, Adolph Weinmuller, András Adorján, Victor Aitay, William Alwyn, Daniele Amfitheatrof, George Antheil, Associated Music Publishers, Frederic Balazs, Erno Balogh, Edward B. Benjamin, Theodor Berger, Lajos Berkovits, Elmer Bernstein, Leonard Bernstein, Walther Bernt, Boston Symphony Orchestra, Boyd Neel Orchestra, Breitkopf & Härtel, The British Broadcasting Corp., Samuel Bronston, Broude Brothers, H. Arthur Brown, Capitol Records Inc., Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Chappell & Company, Ltd., Chicago Symphony Orchestra, Charles-David Colon, Columbia Records, Manuel Compinsky, Aaron Copland, Dallas Symphony Orchestra, Leo Damiani, Jeffrey Dane, Decca Records Inc., Detroit Symphony Orchestra, Marchesa Madeda Mina DiSospiro, Jeno Donath, Ernst & Kurt Eulenburg, Edith Farnadi, Sidney Fischgrund, John Fitzpatrick, Frankisches Landesorcheste, Jack Gallagher, Leo Genn, Glendale Symphony Orchestra Association, Hermann Grabner, Johnny Green, Bernard Herrmann, Hessischer Rundfunk, Hollywood Bowl, John Houseman, J. Paul Getty Museum, Marvel Jensen, Dennis G. Karzag, Alexander Korda, Zoltan Korda, Fritz Lang, Leeds Music Corp., Margit Mantica, Mayo Clinic, Mehli Mehta, Zubin Mehta, Yehudi Menuhin, Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, Midland Bank Ltd., Musicians Union Local 47, National Association for American Composers and Conductors, National Symphony, Eugene Ormandy, Christopher Palmer, Eric Parkin, Leonard Pennario, the Performing Right Society, Ltd., the Philadelphia Orchestra Association, Philharmonia Orchestra of London, Philarmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles, André Previn, Radio Corporation of America, Günter Raphael, Robbins Music Corporation, Imre Rózsa, Juliet Rózsa, Nicholas Rózsa, Margaret Rózsa, Screen Composers Association, Albert Sendrey, Max Steiner, Irving Stone, Syracuse University, Erzsébet Tusa, the University of Southern California, Peter Ustinov, Vanguard Films, Inc., Robert Vansittart, Vox Productions, Franz Waxman, John Waxman, William Morris Agency, Eugene Zador, Sam Zimbalist, and Pinchas Zukerman.
2607208
Biographical History
Miklós Rózsa (1907-1995) was born on April 18, 1907, in Budapest, Hungary. He developed an appreciation for music from his mother, a classical pianist, and his father, an industrialist and lover of folk music. Rózsa began to study the violin at the age of five. Within two years, he had composed a "Student March." Living on the estate of his father, who had extensive landholdings in Nagylocz, Nograd County, northern Hungary, Rózsa often heard the folk songs of the indigenous Paloc people, whose melodies would later influence his compositions.
After Rózsa completed high school in 1925, at age eighteen, he matriculated at the Leipzig Conservatory, Germany, where he studied music and chemistry. By the time Rózsa graduated in 1929, Breitkopf and Härtel had already published his String Trio, op. 1 (1927), and Quintet for Piano and Strings, op. 2 (1928). His next compositions were influenced by Hungarian folk tunes, due in part to a journal he recovered that contained the notations he had written upon hearing the music in his youth.
The composer remained in Leipzig until the rise of Nazism prompted him to leave Germany. In 1931 he arrived in Paris, France, where he was relatively unknown. Though Rózsa's years in Paris produced several compositions, including Theme, Variations, and Finale op. 13 (1933), Rózsa struggled to support himself. In 1935 Rózsa moved to London to score the music for Thunder in the City (1937), a film for Hungarian writer Akos Tolnay. Rózsa also had the fortune of working for Alexander Korda of London Films to compose the music for Knight Without Armour (1937). Rózsa worked with the Kordas on many later projects, including The Four Feathers (1939), The Thief of Baghdad (1940), and Jungle Book (1942).
Rózsa continued to compose orchestral, chamber, and choral works. He received Budapest's Franz Josef Prize for Composition in 1937 and 1938. His Three Hungarian Sketches, op. 14 (1938), was performed in Baden-Baden, Germany at the International Music Festival with great success in 1939.
Rózsa moved to Los Angeles, California in 1940. In August 1943 he married Margaret Finlason, a former actress and secretary to Gracie Fields; the pair had met during Rózsa's film work at Denham Studios, London. At that time, Rózsa also began his long collaboration with writer and director Billy Wilder. His scores for Wilder include Five Graves to Cairo (1943), Double Indemnity (1944), The Lost Weekend (1945), and Fedora (1978). Rózsa's work on Double Indemnity caught the attention of Alfred Hitchcock, who engaged him for work on Spellbound (1945), which earned Rózsa his first Academy Award.
In 1945 Rózsa joined the faculty of the University of Southern California as Professor of Film Music, a position he held for twenty years. In 1946 he became a United States citizen. The late 1940s saw his film work for producer Mark Hellinger on three gangster films, The Killers (1946), Brute Force (1947), and The Naked City (1948). Rózsa's music from The Killers later inspired Walter Schumann's famous four-note "Dragnet" theme, which is now credited to both men following litigation.Rózsa won a second Academy Award for his score of A Double Life (1948). The next year, he signed a contract with Metro Goldwyn Mayer, an agreement that resulted in a decade-long golden era whose pinnacle was Ben-Hur (1959), which earned Rózsa his third and final Oscar.
Rózsa's many orchestral, chamber, and choral compositions include "To Everything There Is A Season," op. 21 (1946); Sinfonia Concertante, op. 29 (1964), written for Jascha Heifetz and Gregor Piatigorsky; Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, op. 31 (1967), written for Leonard Pennario; Tripartita, op. 33 (1972), which Rózsa wrote from his summer home in Santa Margherita, Italy; and Toccata Capricciosa for Solo Cello, op. 36 (1977).
In addition to his composition work, Rózsa conducted worldwide concert performances and recordings; maintained a collection of fine art; penned his autobiography, Double Life: The Autobiography of Miklós Rózsa (1982); and cared for his children, Juliet and Nicholas.Rózsa composed film music until 1982, when he had his first stroke. He continued to work until further strokes impaired his vision and speech. Rózsa died of pneumonia on July 27, 1995 at eighty-eight years old.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Miklós Rózsa Papers is divided into eight series.
Correspondence-subject files contains letters from fellow musicians, conductors, and composers (including Leonard Bernstein, Aaron Copland, Johnny Green, Bernard Herrmann, Henry Mancini, and Eugene Ormandy), music organizations, music publishers, filmmakers (including Samuel Bronston, Ray Harryhausen, Alexander Korda, Alain Resnais, David O. Selznick, and Sam Zimbalist), relatives, and fans with whom Rózsa maintained regular contact.
Fan mail contains letters, cards, and photographs from admirers in chronological order from 1940-1995. Undated fan mail is in a folder at the end of the series.
Compositions contains Rózsa's Opp. 1-45 (except Op. 11) as well as compositions without opus numbers. Some compositions are handwritten while others are printed publications. Additionally, it contains musical compositions by Rózsa's colleagues and friends, including Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Kurt Hessenburg, and Günter Raphael.
Film music includes arrangements and bound scores. Arrangements include selections from Rózsa's film music scores in the form of handwritten scores, sheet music, and reproductions in a copyist's hand. Bound scores include Rózsa's compositions for motion pictures that are in hardcover or spiral-bound format. Some scores are handwritten by the composer (including The Golden Voyage of Sinbad and The V.I.P.s) while others are reproductions in a copyist's hand (including A Double Life, Ben-Hur, and Spellbound).
Memorabilia comprises award certificates, plaques and statues (including Rózsa's 1960 Academy Award for his Ben-Hur score). It includes film memorabilia (such as music cue sheets and film stills), financial documents (including papers relating to Rózsa's property, automobiles, and income taxes), legal documents, miscellany (including documents regarding Rózsa's art collection, draft papers, his address book, medical documents, passports, and writing implements). It also includes photographs and film negatives.
Printed material includes articles and clippings from 1930-1996, concert programs from 1918-1995, press notices for Rózsa's compositions, and publicity documents.
Commercial recordings includes commercially-produced phonograph records and compact discs of recorded music composed or conducted primarily by Rózsa.
Non-commercial recordings contains phonodiscs and tape reels made by Rozsa. The majority are of music composed or conducted by Rozsa, but there are a few spoken-word items such as an interview, a panel discussion, and a speech by Winston Churchill.
Writings includes writings by Rózsa and writings by others. Rózsa's writings include books to which he has contributed an introduction, his autobiography in Hungarian, lists, drafts, notes, music fragments, and manuscripts for lectures and articles. Writings by others comprise manuscripts by Rózsa's colleagues, friends, and critics. Some writings are about Rózsa while others are unrelated (such as Stephen Lovas's My Two Failures).
Arrangement of the Collection
Compositions by Rózsa, Film music, and Recordings are arranged alphabetically by title of work. Compositions by others, Correspondence-subject files, and Writings are arranged alphabetically by creator or subject. Fan Mail is arranged in chronological order with undated materials at the end of the series.
Related Material
Additional sound recordings stored at Syracuse University Library's Belfer Audio Laboratory and Archive. See also the
Gregg Nestor Collection Relating to Miklos Rosza
.
Separated Material
Issues of Pro Musica Sana, published by the Miklós Rózsa Society, have been transfered to Rare Books and are searchable through.
Subject and Genre Headings
Music; Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Abravanel, Maurice, 1903-1993.; Achron, Joseph, 1886-1943.; Adorján, András, 1944-; Aitay, Victor.; Alwyn, William, 1905-1985.; Amfitheatrof, Daniele.; Antheil, George, 1900-1959.; Balazs, Frederic, 1920-; Balogh, Ernõ.; Benjamin, Edward B.; Berger, Theodor, 1905-1992.; Berkovits, Lajos.; Bernstein, Elmer.; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990.; Bernt, Walther.; Bronston, Samuel.; Brown, H. Arthur.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968.; Colon, Charles-David.; Compinsky, Manuel, approximately 1902-1989.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Damiani, Leo.; Dane, Jeffrey.; Di Sospiro, Madeda Mina.; Donath, Jeno.; Farnadi, Edith.; Fischgrund, Sidney.; Fitzpatrick, John.; Francis, Muriel Bultman.; Gallagher, Jack, 1947-; Genn, Leo, 1905-1978.; Grabner, Hermann, 1886-1969.; Green, Johnny, 1908-1989.; Herrmann, Bernard, 1911-1975.; Houseman, John, 1902-1988.; Jensen, Marvel.; Karzag, Dennis G.; Korda, Alexander, Sir, 1893-1956.; Korda, Zoltan, 1895-1961.; Lang, Fritz, 1890-1976.; Mantica, Margit.; Mehta, Mehli.; Mehta, Zubin.; Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999.; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985.; Palmer, Christopher.; Parkin, Eric.; Pedevilla, Giovanni.; Pennario, Leonard.; Previn, André, 1929-; Raphael, Günter, 1903-1960.; Rózsa, Imre.; Rózsa, Juliet.; Rózsa, Margaret.; Rózsa, Miklós, 1907-1995.; Rózsa, Nicholas.; Schulhof, Andrew.; Sendrey, Albert, 1911-2003.; Steiner, Max, 1888-1971.; Stone, Irving, 1903-1989.; Tusa, Erzsébet.; Ustinov, Peter.; Vansittart, Robert Gilbert Vansittart, Baron, 1881-1957.; Waxman, Franz, 1906-1967.; Waxman, John.; Wilson, Harry Robert, 1901-1968.; Zádor, Eugene, 1894-1977.; Zimbalist, Sam.; Zukerman, Pinchas, 1948-; Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.; All Nations Exchange.; Associated Music Publishers.; Boston Symphony Orchestra.; Boyd Neel London String Orchestra.; Breitkopf & Härtel.; British Broadcasting Corporation.; Broude Brothers Limited.; Capitol Records, Inc.; Chappell & Company, Limited.; Chicago Symphony Orchestra.; Columbia Records, Inc.; Dallas Symphony Orchestra.; Decca Records (Firm); Detroit Symphony Orchestra.; Eulenburg, Ernst, firm.; Fränkisches Landesorchester.; Glendale Symphony Orchestra Association.; J. Paul Getty Museum.; John Feher & Company.; Hessischer Rundfunk.; Hollywood Bowl (Los Angeles, Calif.); Leeds Music Corporation.; Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra.; Mayo Clinic.; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.; Midland Bank Limited.; National Association for American Composers and Conductors.; National Symphony Orchestra (Washington, D.C.); Nürnberger Symphoniker.; Performing Right Society.; Philadelphia Orchestra Association.; Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Philharmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles.; Radio Corporation of America.; Robbins Music Corp.; Schweizerische Rundspruchgesellschaft.; Screen Composers Association.; Syracuse University.; University of Southern California.; Vanguard Films (Los Angeles, Calif.); Vox Productions.; Weinmüller, Adolph, firm, Munich.; Westminster Recording Co.; William Morris Agency.; Composers.; Conductors (Music); Hungarian Americans.; Motion picture music -- Scores.; Motion picture music -- United States.; Music -- 20th century.; Musicians.; Orchestral music -- Scores.; Articles.; Audiotapes.; Bank statements.; CD-ROMs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts.; Correspondence.; Musical scores.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Programs (documents); Sheet music.; Sound recordings.; Tape reels.; Composers.; Conductors.; Musicians.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Researcher access to recordings requires advance notice in order to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Majority of collection, gift of Miklos Rózsa, 1965; Miklos Rózsa Society.
Portions of the collection, gift of Nicholas Rozsa.
Portions of the collection, gift of Christopher Palmer.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files, general correspondence
  - A (Box 8)
  - AECO Corporation (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 8)
  - A. N. Abell (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 8)
  - Abeles & Bernstein (New York, NY), lawyer (Box 8)
  - Abravanel, Maurice, musician (Box 8)
  - Académé des Arts et Techniques du Cinéma (Paris, France) (Box 8)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (Hollywood, CA) (Box 8)
  - Academy Transfer (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 8)
  - Access Elevator Corp. (Burbank, CA) (Box 8)
  - Achron, Joseph, composer (Box 8)
  - Adolph Weinmüller (Box 8)
  - Adorján, András, musician (Box 8)
  - Agenzia Rivoli (Rome, Italy) (Box 8)
  - Aitay, Victor, musician (Box 8)
  - Ajmo, M. Benoit, fan (Box 8)
  - Al Axelrod Foreign Car Service (West Hollywood, CA) (Box 8)
  - Albert, Ernst (Box 8)
  - Albingia (Stuttgart, W. Germany) (Box 8)
  - Alec Tiranti, Ltd. (London, England) (Box 8)
  - Alexander Broude, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 8)
  - Alexander, Jeff, composer (Box 8)
  - Alexander Korda Film Productions Ltd. (Middlesex, England), See also Alexander Korda Films, Incorporated (Hollywood, CA) (Box 8)
  - Alexander Korda Films, Incorporated (Hollywood, CA), See also Alexander Korda Film Productions Ltd. (Middlesex, England) (Box 8)
  - All Nations Exchange (New York, NY) (Box 8)
  - Allied Artists Pictures of Canada Ltd. (Toronto, Canada) (Box 8)
  - Alligo, Santo, artist (Box 8)
  - Alpheus Music Corp. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 8)
  - Alves, Cristina, fan (Box 8)
  - Alwyn, William, composer (Box 8)
  - Ambassador of the Hungarian People's Republic, London (Box 8)
  - Ambassador of the Hungarian People's Republic, Washington, D.C. (Box 8)
  - Ameran Films Ltd. (London, England), See also Andor Films Limited; Ashmore, Larry (Box 8)
  - American Embassy Rome (Box 8)
  - American Express (Box 8)
  - American Federation of Musicians (Box 8)
  - American-Hungarian Foundation (Box 8)
  - American Hungarian Relief (Box 8)
  - American Hungarian Studies Foundation (New Brunswick, NJ) (Box 8)
  - American Kennel Club (Box 8)
  - American Music Center (New York, NY) (Box 8)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors & Publishers (ASCAP) (Box 8)
  - American Youth Symphony (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 8)
  - Amfitheatrof, Daniele, composer (Box 8)
  - Amos, David, musician (Box 8)
  - Anda, Géza, musician (Box 9)
  - Andersen, Lilian, fan (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Agnes, realtor (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Carl, realtor (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Michael, writer (Box 9)
  - Andor Films Limited, See also Ameran Films Ltd. (London, England) (Box 9)
  - Antheil, George, composer (Box 9)
  - Anthon, Borwin, conservator (Box 9)
  - Applewhite Mortgage and Investment Company (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 9)
  - Arbatsky, Yury, composer (Box 9)
  - Argus (Stuttgart, W. Germany) (Box 9)
  - Arlen, Walter, critic (Box 9)
  - Arnaz, Desi, musician (Box 9)
  - Arnell, Richard (Tony), composer (Box 9)
  - Arrangers and Orchestrators (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 9)
  - Ashmore, Larry, musician; See also Ameran Films Ltd. (London, England) (Box 9)
  - Associated Music Publishers, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 9)
  - Associated Musicians, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 9)
  - Atkins, Irene Kahn, historian (Box 9)
  - Association Miklós Rózsa, France, See also Borie, Bertrand (Box 9)
  - Audykowski, Andrea (Box 9)
  - Aunt Amy, family (aunt) (Box 9)
  - Auric, Georges, composer (Box 9)
  - Automobile Club of Southern California (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 9)
  - Ava Gardener Museum (Smithfield, NC) (Box 9)
  - Ave, Mildred & Kvortek, John, violin maker (Box 9)
  - Avery, John, fan (Box 9)
  - Avis (Box 9)
  - Award Productions (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 9)
  - B (Box 10)
  - BIEM (Paris, France) (Box 10)
  - Bakman, Simon, musician (Box 10)
  - Balazs, Frederic, musician (Box 10)
  - Baldini, Martha, neighbor in Santa Margherita, Italy (Box 10)
  - Bales, Richard, musician (Box 10)
  - Ballerino, Mel, businessman (Box 10)
  - Balogh, Endre, musician (Box 10)
  - Balogh, Erno, musician (Box 10)
  - Ban, Leslie and Nancy (Box 10)
  - Banca d'America e d"Italia (Box 10)
  - Bank of America (Box 10)
  - Barany, Robert (Box 10)
  - Barbirolli, John and Evelyn, musician (Box 10)
  - Barger, Gustav (Box 10)
  - Barr, George, artist (Box 10)
  - Bart Associates (Los Angeles, CA), agent (Box 10)
  - Bart-Milander Associates, Inc. (North Hollywood, CA), agent (Box 10)
  - Barth, Hermann, fan (Box 10)
  - Basserman, Hans, musician (Box 10)
  - Bathori, Jane, singer (Box 10)
  - Bato, Joseph, artist (Box 10)
  - [The] Baton Press Limited (Southborough, Tunbridge Wells, Kent, England), publisher (Box 10)
  - Bay, Victor (Box 10)
  - Bayer, Harald, fan (Box 10)
  - Bayerischer Rundfunk (Munich W. Germany) (Box 10)
  - Beecham, Thomas, musician (Box 10)
  - Beek, J., musician (Box 10)
  - Beglarian, Grant, composer (Box 10)
  - Behlmer, Rudy and Stacey, writer (Box 10)
  - Bekins Van & Storage Co. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 10)
  - Belinda Harley Associates (London, England), publicist (Box 10)
  - Ben Hur Journal (Box 10)
  - Benjamin, Edward B., businessman (Box 10)
  - Bennett, Gordon (Box 10)
  - Bensussen, Louis (Box 10)
  - Berger, Barbara, fan (Box 11)
  - Berger, Theodor, composer (Box 11)
  - Berkovits, Lajos, family (uncle) (Box 11)
  - Berkovits, Regina, family (mother); See Rozsa, Regina.
  - Berliner Festwochen (Box 11)
  - Berman, Pandro, producer (Box 11)
  - Bernstein, Elmer and Eve, composer (Box 11)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, musician (Box 11)
  - Bernt, Walther (Box 11)
  - Berthelot, Domy P. (Box 11)
  - Bertoli, Julius Karr, musician (Box 11)
  - Bettelheim, Wilhelm, fan (Box 11)
  - [The] Big Three Music Corp. (New York, NY) (Box 11)
  - Bischoff, A., M.D., physician (Box 11)
  - Bissett, Robert W. (Box 11)
  - Blakely, Colin, actor (Box 11)
  - Bomblin, Gilbert, fan (Box 11)
  - Bonham's (London, England) (Box 11)
  - Bookraft (Hollywood, CA) (Box 11)
  - Boosey and Hawkes (New York and London), publisher (Box 11)
  - Boren & Company (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 11)
  - Borie, Bertrand, writer (Box 11)
  - Bosch, Fritz (Box 11)
  - [The] Boston Pops (Box 11)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra (Box 11)
  - Bottegg Antiquaria (Box 11)
  - Boxall, Harold, producer (Box 11)
  - [The] Boyd Neel Orchestra (London, England) (Box 12)
  - Boyer, Charles, critic (Box 12)
  - Brandao, Antoine (Box 12)
  - Brandt & Brandt, agent (Box 12)
  - Breitkopf & Härtel (Wiesbaden, W. Germany), publisher; See also Sievers, Lieselotte (Box 12)
  - Bremner, Tony, composer (Box 13)
  - Breyer, Wolfgang, fan (Box 13)
  - Brigham Young University (Box 13)
  - Brighton's Rare Recordings (Santa Monica, CA) (Box 13)
  - British Broadcasting Corp. (Box 13)
  - British and Continental Music Agencies, Ltd. (London, England), publisher (Box 13)
  - [The] British Film Academy (London England) (Box 13)
  - Broadcast Music, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 13)
  - Brodszky, Nicholas (Box 13)
  - Broglia, Valerio (Box 13)
  - Bronfeld, Myron, fan (Box 13)
  - Bronston, Samuel, producer (Box 13)
  - Broude Brothers Music (New York), publisher (Box 13)
  - Brown, H. Arthur, musician (Box 13)
  - Bureau Hongrois Pour La Protection Des Droits D'Auteur (Budapest, Hungary) (Box 13)
  - Burrelle's Press Clipping Bureau, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 13)
  - Bush, Martin (Box 13)
  - Butler, Herbert, fan (Box 13)
  - C (Box 13)
  - CARE (Box 13)
  - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, musician (Box 13)
  - Cagney, William, actor (Box 13)
  - Cale, Terry (Box 13)
  - (State of) California Dept. of Motor Vehicles (Box 13)
  - (State of) California, Franchise Tax Commissioner (Box 13)
  - California Hungarians (Box 13)
  - Callaway, Paul, conductor (Box 13)
  - Calligaris, Sergio, musician (Box 13)
  - Cambren, Oliver M. (Box 13)
  - Camelich, Ellen (Box 13)
  - Cameo Music Reproduction, Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 13)
  - Campbell Horticultural Co. (Santa Barbara, CA) (Box 13)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corp. (Box 13)
  - Canadian Film Awards (Box 13)
  - Capitol Records Inc. (Box 14)
  - Caplan-Mintz, Toby, musician (Box 14)
  - Capra, Frank, director; See United States Army (Box 14)
  - Caps, John, writer (Box 14)
  - Carlo Pedevilla, Spedizioni Marittime (Genova, Italy), See also Giovanni Pedevilla (Genova, Italy) (Box 14)
  - Carmirelli, Pina, musician (Box 14)
  - Carnazzo, George (Box 14)
  - Carpetcraft, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 14)
  - Carroll, Des (Box 14)
  - Carmichael Forwarding Service (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 14)
  - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario and Clara, composer (Box 14)
  - Castillo-Gomez, Antonio (Box 14)
  - Caston, Saul, musician (Box 14)
  - Cedars of Lebanon Hospital (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 14)
  - Challenge Upholstering and Mattress Co. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 14)
  - Challis, Haylyn-Victor, fan (Box 14)
  - Chambers Green, Ltd., See also Green, Ray (Box 14)
  - Chapman College (Los Angeles, CA), See also Pollak, Robert (Box 14)
  - Chappell & Co. Ltd. (Box 14)
  - Charles Ede Limited (Box 14)
  - Charles, Ryan & Rivers (Box 14)
  - Chemiserie Moderne (Zurich, Switzerland) (Box 14)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra (Chicago, IL) (Box 14)
  - Christiansen, Olaf C., conductor (Box 14)
  - Christie, Manson and Woods, Ltd. (Christie's) (Box 14)
  - Chuck's Painting Co. (Reseda, CA) (Box 14)
  - Clerk of Los Angeles Municipal Court (Box 14)